Finding Aid for Dignity/Detroit Records, 1974-2004
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
Dignity/Detroit Records 1974-2004
Dignity/Detroit.
2.3 linear ft.
04103 Ba 2
Organization established to unite gay Catholics and provide a vehicle through which they might be heard within the Church and by the wider Detroit community. Organizational files; Executive Council and general membership meeting records; and programs and other materials of organization anniversaries, retreats, and other activities.
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
The records came from Dignity/Detroit (donor no. 9512 ) in September 2004.
The record group is open to research.
Dignity Detroit was established in 1974. Its purpose was to unite gay Catholics and to provide an instrument through which they might be heard by the Church and by the wider Detroit community. The organization was managed by a Council of Dignity members. There was also a Board of Directors to serve in an advisory capacity composed of both members and non-members. Dignity Detroit had four standing committees to serve the needs of members in areas of Spiritual Formation (developing Christian maturity in members), Education (raising consciousness of members to their rights and responsibilities as Catholic Christians and members of society), Social Involvement (primarily concerned with the protections of their civil rights), and Social (social and recreational activities).
The records of Dignity Detroit include the organization's constitution and articles of incorporation, minutes, correspondence, and other materials documenting its administration and activities. The records have been arranged into the following series: Organizational Files; Executive Council; General Meeting records; and Anniversaries, retreats, and other activities.
Subjects:
Dignity/Detroit.; Gays--Religious life--Michigan--Detroit.; Catholic gays--Michigan; Detroit (Mich.)--Church history.; Catholic Church--Michigan--Detroit.
- Organizational Files
  - Dignity, Inc. National Office materials
    - Position and purpose, 1997 (Box 1)
    - Constitution and bylaws (Box 1)
  - Articles of incorporation (Box 1)
  - Annual reports-Non-Profit Organizations (Box 1)
  - Changes in Registered Office or Resident Agent (Box 1)
  - Constitutions (Box 1)
  - Tax Exemption Records (Box 1)
- Executive Council
  (minutes, correspondence, and related materials)
  - 1976-1991, 15 folders (Box 1)
    (some gaps in dates)
  - 1991-2004, 12 folders (Box 2)
- General Meeting
  - 1974-1980, 1 binder (Box 2)
- Anniversaries, retreats, and other activities
  - Anniversary booklets, 1975-2004 (Box 2)
  - Retreats, 1984-1989, 8 folders (Box 3)
  - Retreats, 1998-2002, 6 folders (Box 3)
  - Prayer services, vigils, etc., 10 folders (Box 3)
  - Communication Workshop, 1987 (Box 3)
  - Relationship Enhancement Seminar, 1985 (Box 3)